Thomas Ball

Phone: +44 (0) 7754 322 413

Email: bomtall1@hotmail.com

Website: botmall.github.io/website

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/thomas-ball-9115501b5/

Address: 116 Forest Lane, Harrogate, HG2 7EG

Objective

Having recently gone back into education as a mature student to study Mathematics and Computer Science A-Levels, I am looking for a degree apprenticeship where I can make use of these skills. Working as a Painter & Decorator for the past 11 years, I understand the importance of customer relations and the economies of running a business. I am proud that our customer base is built solely from personal recommendation, since this demonstrates my ability to build trust and good professional relationships with customers. I am a hard-working and motivated individual who strives for excellence, which has been developed whilst working on large scale construction and specialist restoration projects. I am looking forward to applying this experience in a new area.

Experience

Painter & Decorator | Sep 2010 – Present Self employed

- Development of good customer relations & project management.
- Achieving excellence through attention to detail & interior design knowledge.
- Negotiating bulk and discounted material costs to increase profit margins.

Climbing Instructor | Sep 2014 - Dec 2015

Harrogate Climbing Centre

- Introducing people to safe indoor climbing from 5 years old to adults.
- Managing safe group sessions indoors & out.
- > This role required the interpersonal skills to help motivate and support clients.

Clerical Officer | 2007 - Aug 2010

The Royal Bank of Scotland Group

- Phone operator handling security checks on potentially fraudulent & high value transactions.
- Escalated an idea for a solution which would improve efficiency. This was then implemented.

Education

Current Studies | April 2020 - Present

- Self-studying Mathematics A Level
- Computer Science A Level with Pembrokeshire College

Harrogate Grammar School | 2002 - 2007

- A Levels: Art (C)
- GCSEs: Mathematics (A), English (A), Geography (A), English Lit (B), Physics (B), Chemistry (B), Biology (B), Religious Studies (B), History (C), IT (C), Art & Design (C)

Other accomplishments

- NFCE Level 3 in Creative Craft
- NFCE Level 1 in Photography

Coding

Languages: Python (intermediate), HTML (basic), Git (intermediate), Jupyter (intermediate)

Projects: Website, RemoteQuote which can be found on my website

Extra-curricular

Climbing – From my experience as a climber I have developed navigation and safety skills. It requires good communication and working as a team. I am passionate about climbing and really enjoy exploring new locations.

Yoga – My wife is a qualified yoga instructor and I regularly participate and help her to market her classes.

Home – Recently, I completed an extensive renovation on our property.

Other Skills

Hold a full clean driving license

Competent with computer applications such as Word, Power point, Excel and Outlook

References

Professional references can be provided on request.